{"Topic": "Ancient Indian History", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "tiple Choice G.K. Questions - Ancient Indian History", "op1": "Kanishka", "op2": "Kadphises-1", "op3": "Vasudeva", "op4": "Kushanas", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Mathura school of art flourished during the reign of", "op1": "Hiuen-Tsang", "op2": "Fa- Hien", "op3": "Marco Polo", "op4": "Nicolo Conti", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following travelers visited India during the Gupta period?", "op1": "Ashoka", "op2": "Chandragupta II", "op3": "Samudragupta", "op4": "Kharavela", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Hathigumpha inscription is attributed to which of the following emperors?", "op1": "Guptas", "op2": "Kushanas", "op3": "Mauryas", "op4": "Palas", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The illustrious names of Aryabhatta and Varahamihir are associated with the age of the", "op1": "Chalukya raids", "op2": "Greek invasion", "op3": "Hun invasion", "op4": "Pallava raids", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Gupta empire declined in the fifth century A. D. as a consequence of", "op1": "Harsha", "op2": "Ashok", "op3": "Kanishka", "op4": "Chandragupta 2", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "During whose reign did the Gandhara School of art blossom?", "op1": "Ujjain", "op2": "Kasi", "op3": "Kausambi", "op4": "Ayodhya", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The capital of Kosala kingdom was -", "op1": "Mauryan", "op2": "Haryanka", "op3": "Nanda", "op4": "Kushan", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Bimbisara belonged to which of the following dynasties?", "op1": "Hiuen-Tsang", "op2": "Megasthenese", "op3": "I Ching", "op4": "Fahien", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who among the following foreigners was the first to visit India?", "op1": "Harappan period", "op2": "Mauryan period", "op3": "Buddhist period", "op4": "Gupta period", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Ajanta painting belongs to the", "op1": "Gandhara", "op2": "Sarnath", "op3": "Mathura", "op4": "All of the above", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which one of the following schools of sculpture thrived during the post-Ashokan period?", "op1": "50 BC", "op2": "28 AD", "op3": "78 AD", "op4": "129 AD", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The Saka Era commenced in", "op1": "Bimbisara", "op2": "Chandragupta Maurya", "op3": "Ashoka", "op4": "Pushyamitra Sunga", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following was a contemporary of Alexander the Great?", "op1": "Chandragupta Maurya", "op2": "Samudra Gupta", "op3": "Vikramaditya", "op4": "Skand Gupta", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Whose achievements are recorded in the Allahabad Pillar inscription?", "op1": "Kalyan", "op2": "Tamralipti", "op3": "Sopara", "op4": "Baroch", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The temple of Konark was built by Narasimha of the", "op1": "Maratha Administration", "op2": "Chola Administration", "op3": "Ganga Administration", "op4": "Vijayanagar Administration", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Alexander, the Great invaded India during the rule of -", "op1": "Ajatshatru", "op2": "Bimbisara", "op3": "Dhana Nanda", "op4": "Mahapadma Nanda", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Alexander defeated Porus in 326 B. C. at the battle of :", "op1": "Thaneshwar", "op2": "Tarain", "op3": "Peshawar", "op4": "Hydaspes", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which among the following is the oldest dynasty?", "op1": "Maurya", "op2": "Gupta", "op3": "Kushan", "op4": "Kanva", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which rulers built the Ellora temples?", "op1": "Chalukya", "op2": "Sunga", "op3": "Rashtrakuta", "op4": "Pallava", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Who started the Saka Era which is still used by the Government of India?", "op1": "Kanishka", "op2": "Vikramaditya", "op3": "Samudra Gupta", "op4": "Asoka", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The great silk-route to the Indians was opened by -", "op1": "Kanishka", "op2": "Ashoka", "op3": "Harsha", "op4": "Fa-Hien", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Aryabhatta, believed to have been born in the 5th century AD, was a most renowned scholar of", "op1": "Astronomy", "op2": "Biology", "op3": "Medicine", "op4": "Physiology", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Iron Pillar at Mehrauli in Delhi is believed to record the achievements of", "op1": "Ashoka", "op2": "Chandragupta Maurya", "op3": "Samudragupta", "op4": "Chandragupta 2", "Answer": 4}]}